Wise man Daniel moves through the congregation praying for the people in the power of the Holy Ghost.
As he ministers the prayer to the people every garment of darkness in their lives are removed in Jesus' name.
Jesus came to preserve us, to heal us, to deliver us and save us.
Get ready to see and understand that there is more to life than meets the ordinary eye,
as you watch wise man Daniel's encounter with this man.
Who are you?
Chief priest.
Chief priest?
Yes.
What have you done to him?
Destroyed him.
Destroyed him?
Yes.
Can you explain how you destroyed him?
We've ruined his business. We've ruined his marriage.
We've just finished him. By the way, he's supposed to die today.
He's supposed to...
Die today.
Why is he here? We have an arrangement here.
Speak louder!
I'm speaking. I'm chief priest, okay?
He's supposed to come home today.
You're a chief priest?
Yes.
What have you done to the family?
We destroyed their businesses, there's no progress there.
What have you done to the marriage?
I sent the wife away with the daughter.
You sent the wife away with the daughter.
Yes.
And people that owe him... We removed his memory and he doesn't remember.
So those who owe him - you have removed his memory so he's not able to remember those who are owing him.
Yes.
Why did you do that?
Oh! He's a bit smart. So we have to be taking his memory as he ages, you know.
So every year we remove a 12 months memory capacity from his brain.
Why?
We need to slow him down.
What kind of business does he do? What kind of business do you destroy?
He has a good big supermarket, a popular supermarket. We destroyed it.
He has a good pharmacy, a household pharmacy.
We just finished it. By the way, if he thinks to continue to run that business,
if he's not going to die, we will send him to prison
for still trying to overturn our decision. But anyway - he's supposed to die.
When is he supposed to die?
He's supposed to die today. It is the birthday of his daughter.
Birthday of his daughter.
So he has to celebrate her birthday over there
while we watch what happens.
He supposed to commit suicide that's why we brought him home. We didn't want him to come in cargo.
Where was he living before?
He stays in Botswana.
And you brought him home?
Yes.
Why did you bring him home? Why?
We don't want him to come in cargo. We want him to die at home
because we need fresh blood. I've got to go.
You've got to go.
I've got to go.
Okay, you say he's supposed to die today. Why did you allow him to come in here?
See, I don't know. I think he tricked us. That's another thing.
He plays smart.
He plays smart?
He agreed he is coming home to die.
When he got to Lagos he got stick in Lagos. He is supposed to be in the village by now
but he keeps on playing the game.
Okay, and he's finally here. Do you know where he is now?
This place...
It's not good for us.
This place is not good for you people?
Why do you say this place is not good for you, people?
It's a one way house. When you come in, you don't come out.
Why did you say, it's a place you come in - you don't go out? Why?
We can only see footsteps coming in. Where did you send them?
Okay, who are the people that come in and cannot go out? Who are the people?
All the mermaids and kings and queens of the world under the ground.
All the mermaids and kings and queens of the underworld.
Yes.
When they come in, they don't go out.
Yes. Where do you keep them? Just let's have an agreement.
Let's have an understanding. Let me just go, okay?
Okay, why did you say, when they come in here, they don't go out? What is wrong?
That's the strange thing about this house.
That's the strange thing about this house, but one day we're going to find out.
There must be a way out.
Okay, now you've come here? Are you sure, you're still going back?
For me? That's why I said let's have a gentleman's agreement, okay?
We'll leave him to you.
Huh?
It's okay.
Okay. The same thing that has happened to other mermaids and evil spirits, will happen to you now.
Come out, in the mighty name of Jesus! Come here!
Come out, in the mighty name of Jesus!
Out, in the mighty name of Jesus!
You wicked chief priest - out, in the mighty name of Jesus Christ!
Fire all over your body! Fire!
Oh!
Come out, in the mighty name of Jesus!
Out, in the mighty name of Jesus!
You wicked chief priest - out, in the mighty name of Jesus! In Jesus' mighty name!
You're free. Rise up!
How are you, sir?
I'm fine.
Huh? How are you?
How are you, sir?
I'm fine.
What are you doing here?
I'm just wondering.
You said?..
What happened to you? You just stood up from the floor. What happened to you?
Shame! Oh, shame!
How?
What happened to you? You don't know what happened to you?
You mean...
Where were you sitting before?
I was sitting down there.
Then what happened to you? Why are you here?
Okay, you said you are the chief priest in the body.
Priest?
Not only priest - chief priest in the body.
No.
You said so now.
I'm not a priest.
You said you're out to destroy this body and the entire family.
Oh God! How?..
You just said it now - you.
Okay.
You also you said he was in Botswana
and you brought him back, that he's to die today.
Today is the birthday of the daughter and you are meant to die today.
Yes, I stay in Botswana.
But you said you brought him back to kill him.
No, I just came on my own.
You said you brought him to kill him, that today is the birthday of the daughter.
When is the birthday of your daughter?
Today.
You said you want to kill him.
You destroyed all his businesses. He has a pharmaceutical company, you destroyed it.
You didn't say that?
No, my business is having problems, but I can't destroy what I'm building up.
Okay, you are delivered, sir. You are free.
Thank you. Thank You, Jesus, I'm free.
Thank you, so you have listened to everything.
You listened to what has happened?
He received a phone call, he never believed this can happen.
But everything he said in the spirit
reflects what has happened to him in the physical world.
Now he's here today.
Now let us see everything he said. He's now going to take it one by one.
Because he didn't know what he was saying. But all what he said -
is actually what was happenning in his life.
So tell me now what was happening in your life.
If I call my father here to explain what is happening in his life,
you will see that those things can not just come from Heaven - it's from pit of hell.
If those things are from pit of hell, it means definitely you're possesed.
And to go straight to the root of your problem is to deliver you from the demon.
If you are not delivered from the demon
and you are healed - then we are just joking. Let me tell you something.
If the demon is inside person, and the person is healed -
now it's like a man who has gonorrhea,
but as a result the wife also has gonorrhea. But the husband comes here, "Sir, I have gonorrhea, heal me".
If the man is healed of that gonorrhea, you know, he will still go and meet the wife that has that gonorrhea at home.
And the moment he meets that woman for affection,
he will contact another gonorrhea.
This gonorrhea will not go permanently,
unless the same woman is also delivered from the gonorrhea.
If the woman is healed of gonorrhea, and the man is healed of gonorrhea - the gonorrhea is gone.
But if one of them is healed of gonorrhea - we are just playing around.
Can you see the reason why our problem continues to persist?
Imagine, you say you have limitation, problem in your business, you rise to a big position...
You were prayed for and you rise to a big position... Suddenly you - mmm!..
Backwards!
It means we have not touched the root of your problem.
It's, "Poverty! Poverty!"
We pray for you -
and you are blessed, and you get there! Suddenly the whole thing disappears again.
It means something is in you, that will just strike anytime you want to strike.
It will just fold hands. It will allow you to continue to enjoy.
At the time you need that enjoyment most, it will destroy it.
That everything is smooth - it is too early for you to say,
"I'm okay, now". It's too early. Are you sure that old man is delivered?
Are you with me? If I'm talking to you, let me see your hand!
Can you see the root of your problem?
I want you to listen to our brother. You'll learn a lot of lessons today.
We want our brother to tell us, please. Open up, please. With you word - a lot of people will be delivered.
So please, don't be selfish.
To be selfish is not to open up. Now you are delivered.
And you want this deliverance to affect many people positively.
A lot of people - million people, trillion people are watching this program.
So for them to be delivered too - it's a big promotion for you.
I want you to open up. Don't be selfish. Open up, tell us everything what has happened. Thank you.
Your name, your profession, your spiritual life. Are you a Christian? Who are you? Listen.
Viewers all over the world, please, watch and learn:
the experiences and what you are about to hear is greater than miracle.
Why is it greater than miracle?
Because it will help you to maintain miracle.
And what helps you to maintain something you have is greater than that something you have.
Do you know,
maintaince is salvation and salvation is maintainance. If I'm talking to you, let me see your hand.
Tell your neighbour, "Maintenance is salvation, salvation is maintainance".
Emmanuel! My name is Ignatius DJ. I'm Nigerian but I stay in Botswana.
I was here last Monday service and what I experienced was quite strange to me.
As you saw in the clips, when the wise man Daniel was passing and laying hands,
I found out that just in a second I could not understand myself, the next second I came to my senses, the next second I didn't understand.
But after the deliverance when they put back to me what I said,
even they wrote it down for me, and I listened and I saw the clips again -
I was more confused as to what had really happened.
But I must say between then and now I've been trying to figure out
how all these things started, how it relates to my life because I consider myself a Christian
and active Christian for that matter. I do pray, I do counsil others as a service to my church.
I hold responsibilities, I advise people.
Sure, I'm an elder in the church. And when this happened I tried to reflect on my Christian life
as to what I had been doing before and how this spirit had been in me.
Then when I looked at my life, I found out I had problems
but a problem of inconsistency in activities in relationship even now
business relationships, fellow male to male relationships and just like that.
But I would say the greatest point where my spiritual entanglement in my physical life manifested -
is in my marital life.
In Botswana, I run a pharmacy business but I'm not a pharmacist by profession.
I do hire a pharmacists, but just like any other stuff I employ, they hardly stay with me.
People you employ today - tomorrow they leave your employment.
In the midst of trying to save my business,
I was not yet married then, and I decided if I got married to a pharmacist,
it would do me good and help me to run our business as a family.
With that thought, I sent word to my people that I needed a wife on the condition that she would be a pharmacist,
so that we can be able to run our business together. And that was done in 2006.
It is a tradition in our place, if you are far away abroad
and you need to get married, your people arrange for the marriage. They will get you a wife by сommunication,
you see pictures and you feel it's okay. You come home and get married. So that happened to me in 2006.
Precisely, December 17, 2006 I came down from Botswana and by 23rd of December I was in the church.
I wedded to my wife and I went back to my business place.
We never courted before, we never met before our marriage.
Two years later after her school she joined me and that was where my problem of inconsistency in relationship started -
on the very day I picked my wife from the airport.
In fact, it all started as I picked my wife from the airport. We were coming home,
and there wasn't any chat of excitement or just being happy picking your wife.
It is more of as if I was just a driver sent to pick up somebody
and I was just concerned driving and my head was just asking like, "What am I doing?"
By the time we got home I never felt any affection for my wife.
In fact, I just started seeing her as a neighbour roommate with me.
And that really caused a very big strain, that even to the stage I was even asking for a miracle for me
to realize that I'm with my wife - not just another man in the house.
To the lady... She was really going through hell.
But nevertheless, I was in a different world of my own. All my concern was to wake up in the morning,
go to my business and come back in the night. And even at night when I was coming back,
when I remembered that I was going back home to this woman -
I would rather prefer to spend more time outside before going home.
Eventually we managed to make do and she became pregnant.
But by the time she was four months pregnant, I could no longer manage that.
Fortunately enough she has her family away in the United States,
and I arranged and sent her to one of her sisters on the basis that she would have a baby in the United States.
As if to say that was my wish.
But actually it wasn't my wish, it was a way of seeing her out of my life.
So all the time when she was away in the United States for her pregnancy,
I was hopeful and wishing that she will change her mind never to come back to me.
Because I just felt that she was a problem to me and not really a wife.
Fortunately or unfortunately she had a baby and I wasn't excited.
After six months by persuasion, I agreed she will come back.
And when she came back with the baby, after six months I just like before went to the airport.
I first of all took enough time to attend to my bussiness,
and they were waiting for me at the airport.
When I picked her up at the airport,
it was like if I have known I would have arranged a hotel where I would put them,
instead of taking them to my house.
Eventually we came home. I think they came home on Wednesday
and by Friday I put them back on a flight to Nigeria.
By the time they left, my goodness, all I was just doing
was using every means so that she would call it a day.
If I was busy at work or even if I was happy and my phone rang,
once I picked up the phone and it was my wife, - I became annoyed.
This continued, and I felt that "No, I don't want this marriage",
I would rather sacrifice everything for me to walk out of this marriage.
This was happening in 2009.
Between 2009 and now...
Between 2009 and now I was just going out there looking for...
I was no longer looking for wife these days. All I wanted was just to have children here and there.
l felt that because in the society now people make do with single parenthood,
I could always take care of the children, without putting a wife into my house.
And this happened that I am telling you as I'm standing here now.
I have four kids and my wife is not aware of this incident.
And these four kids - just one is from my marriage.
Three kids outside my marriage with three different wives,
three different women.
This thing is just by each one as if it is in program of their activity.
I will just be there and this thing just keeps happening.
In my head, I didn't even have the cause to talk to anybody.
There was something I discuss it in my head, and it just keeped on telling me, "No. This is okay. This is okay".
I found myself the principles I learned from childhood being turned overnight
into what I was just seeing in the present days with my eyes
just believing what my eyes saw and no longer what I had in my head.
As if to say my head didn't belong to me.
At this point in time, it is actually true it was the frustration in my business
that really brought down all the memories of everything.
Since these few days of my deliverance
I feel very much ashamed of all I have done.
All I have been praying is that it is only man of God that can help me
first and foremost in history to reconcile me with my family.
Of everything I have I will let go.
Of everything I have in life I can let go before my wife and my daughter -
I am pleading with the man of God, please help me recover my family first,
my family, my daughter.
It's just now that we meet here at the Synagogue, Church of Nations.
You listen to that?
I cannot continue listen to this, it is very touching. He's crying.
He says it was like his head was no longer his own head.
He had different women outside,
different children - each child for each woman.
It's like this head was no longer his head, he just continued to do the other thing.
After that deliverance on Sunday, and we now called him, all what he said.
He started telling all what happened.
Immediately we asked for the wife's number and I called the woman.
For so long he has been separated with the dear woman and the woman having heard our voice - she came down.
I want to see the woman, please.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Well.
I'm just seeing her for the first time. Face to face.
Because I was very busy for the past... It's alright, don't worry. She wants to clean your eyes.
Please, let her clean your eyes. Have it, little one. You can use it to clean your mum's...
Okay, it's alright.
Since past Sunday now I've been very busy
but just hearing 'TB Joshua', 'The Synagogue' the woman said - whatever the case he handles -
she cannot disobey the man of God, she has to come and explain herself. That is why she's here today.
You know, we are not going to deceive her, we'll tell her the mind of God.
She is a Christian. She realized that in every situation God has something to say.
"Let me hear what this man, what God said to this man?"
That's why she is here. She is not here to meet the man here. But she is here,
"I want to hear what God is talking, is speaking to this man. What message God has given to this man for me?"
That's why she's here. She's not here to meet our father here, but she is here to hear what does God say,
what message this man has for me. That's why she's here, and this is a beautiful lady I see.
Look at the little girl looking like father as well.
Okay, so now you have seen what's happened.
Okay.
You have seen the woman is really crying, you have seen what happened.
It's never his will, this is work of satan.
Satan just wanted to destroy the house
but today we thank God we are able to live to see today.
Look at what happened today and your husband was not here. He was here
to ask God to bless his business, but suddenly the Lord went straight to the root of the problem.
Suddenly.
Just like today by the time we lay hand on you because it's not yet time now to do that
when we are here for reconciliation. By the time we lay hand on you and whatever inside of you also will begin to speak.
This is why everyone of us is here today.
I really want to salute you.
Because you knew the time like this is coming
that is why you have been waiting for time like this.
If not - you would have messed up your life.
But today you refused to mess up your life, you waited for time like this.
She refused to mess up her life. Assume she has messed up her life now -
no more reconciliation. Time like this -
we could not call her to come here. In fact, she would say, "Man of God, I need to ask permission from sososo person",
which I would not even allow her to come here.
But today because she knew that the time like this is coming, she knew satan is a lier,
she has been waiting for the time like this - now the time has come.
So I really want to salute you and to say, "God, what a wonderful woman is this!" Look at my little one.
The little one does not even know the father. Who is that?
Okay. Wait, I'm coming. I want to do... For you to know, satan is a lier.
Look at him!
Who's is it? Who is it?
It's daddy. Baby, say, it's daddy!
It's daddy.
I'm very sorry, help me plead with my wife to forgive me. I'm very sorry!
I'm very sorry, please.
Look, you know we thank God for what God has done even if you walk on your knee to your wife,
it's not too bad. Can you walk on your on your knees now and let me go there.
Give me my little one.
Because it's not even enough to pay the price.
The price is too heavy.
We know, it's not you that has been doing this. It's satan. You have to walk on your knees.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry. I was confused. It wasn't me, it would not happen again.
Please.
Come home. Don't talk of the future now, talk of now.
Because if you now talk of the future, you are confusing the whole thing.
Talk of what happened now. "It won't happen again. I am so sorry!"
Please, I'm so sorry, forgive me, please.
Listen to that. We are not fighting the flesh and blood, it means our husband is not our enemy,
our wife is not our enemy, our children are not our enemies
but spirit being. It is not this flesh, the appearance you are seeing,
that is fighting you, that is destroying the marriage.
It's not this appearance you are looking at that we are fighting, but spirit being, the devil.
So please.
I want to join your family.
Thank you very much. Thank you very much.
Reconciled In Jesus' Name
Say, "Thank you, Jesus!"
Thank You, Jesus!
Say it louder again!
Louder again.
Say, "Thank You, Jesus!"
Thank You, Jesus!
Reconciled In Jesus' Name
Chris, can you help me take them to the restaurant and let them be there and have a chat. I'm coming to meet you
Madam, come. I think once and for all - because
when you are coming next week is thanksgiving, but it's better I should speak my mind now.
So what God deposited in my heart.
Look, you are mother, you are everything. I'm going to join you in this battle. I'm going to join this family.
Our duty now is...
This is the child of the house, but those children at home -
we need to ask where are they, so that we can take care of them. You are a mother.
You are a mother. This is the child of the house. We still have to ask those children.
We want to see them so we can take care of these children.
Take care of them. You are a mother.
We are going to ask those children and bring them home, take care of these children.
Please, I'm coming. Thank you.
Reconciled In Jesus' Name
Can you see God?
Can you see God? What beyond repair...
Beyond repair! Because of that deliverance...
No deliverance - no forgivness. Tell your neighbour.
Tell your neighbour again. I can't hear you.
Uncle, if somebody is telling you that he forgives you, just like that - without deliverance taking place - it is lips.
That forgivness is not from the heart.
If somebody does look at you and say, "I forgive you, I forgive you, it's over. I'm a Christian", - he now lies.
After deliverance that forgivness can come.
No deliverance - no forgiveness.
That's Jesus for you.
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today
And stay up to date for the latest prophecies,
deliverances, sermons and testimonies from the Synagogue, Church of All Nations.
Emmanuel TV - changing lives, changing nations and changing the world.